aspentimes.com 2018-03-01

# Privacy Policy | AspenTimes.com

Effective Date: 10/28/2010

Swift Communications, Inc. (“Swift Communications,” “we,” “us,” and “our”), owns this Web site (this “Site”) and all other sites on which it has posted this Privacy Policy (this “Policy”). This Policy explains how Swift Communications protects your privacy when you use this Site.

## Our Commitment to Transparency

Swift Communications is committed to providing the information you need to make informed choices about the ways you use this Site. This Policy describes the personal information we collect when you use this Site, for example, by registering with this Site, creating a blog, subscribing to one of our newspapers, or submitting news items. It also describes how we use the personal information you share with us and some of the steps we take to protect your privacy.

If you have any questions about this Policy or our privacy practices, please contact us by e-mail at [digitalsupport@aspentimes.com](mailto:digitalsupport@aspentimes.com) or by mail at 314 E. Hyman Ave, #101, Aspen, CO 81611.

## Your Consent

Please take a few minutes to review this Policy before using this Site. By using this Site you are consenting to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information as set forth in this Policy. If you do not agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy, you may not access or use this Site.

## This Policy is Part of Our Terms of Use

This Policy is part of the [Terms of Use](https://www.aspentimes.com/terms-of-use/) that govern your use of this Site. A link to our [Terms of Use](https://www.aspentimes.com/terms-of-use/) is provided at the bottom of each page of this Site.

## This Policy May Change

This Policy describes Swift Communications’ current policies and practices with regard to the personal information we collect through this Site.

We are continually improving and adding to the features and functionality of this Site and the services we offer through this Site. As a result of these changes (or changes in the law), we may need to update or revise this Policy. Accordingly, we reserve the right to update or modify this Policy at any time, without prior notice, by posting the revised version of this Policy behind the link marked “Privacy Policy” at the bottom of each page of this Site. Your continued use of this Site after we have posted the revised Policy constitutes your agreement to be bound by the revised Policy. However, we will honor the terms that were in effect when we gathered data from you.

For your convenience, whenever this Policy is changed, we will alert you by posting a notice on our home page for sixty days. We will also update the “effective date” at the top of this page. If more than sixty days goes by between your visits to this Site, be sure you check the effective date to see if this Policy has been revised since your last visit.

You may access the current version of this Policy at any time by clicking the link marked “Privacy Policy” at the bottom of each page of this Site.

## Privacy Notices

This Policy may be supplemented or amended from time to time by “privacy notices” posted on this Site. These privacy notices provide a level of detail that we cannot provide in this more general description of our privacy practices. For example, certain pages of this Site may contain privacy notices providing details about the personal information we collect on those pages, why we need that information, and choices you may have about the ways we use that information.

## Other Agreements

When you sign up to use a special feature of this Site, you may be asked to agree to special terms governing your use of the special feature. In such cases, you may be asked to expressly consent to the special terms, for example, by checking a box or clicking on a button marked “I agree.” This type of agreement is known as a “click-through” agreement. If any of the terms of the click-through agreement are different than the terms of this Policy, the terms of the click-through agreement will supplement or amend this Policy, but only with respect to the matters governed by the “click-through agreement.”

## Definition of “Personal Information”

“Personal information” means information about an identified or identifiable individual. Examples of personal information include your name, your e-mail address, and your photograph.

## Types of Personal Information We Collect

 _Information You Volunteer_. Swift Communications collects the personal information you and others knowingly and voluntarily provide when you use this Site, for example, the personal information you provide when you register with this Site, create a blog, subscribe to one of our newspapers, or submit news items.  
_  
Information Sent to Us by Your Web Browser_. We collect information that is sent to us automatically by your Web browser. This information typically includes your IP address, the identity of your Internet service provider, the name and version of your operating system, the name and version of your browser, the date and time of your visit, and the pages you visit. Please check your browser if you want to learn what information your browser sends or how to change your settings. Generally, we do not link the information provided by your browser to information that identifies you by name.

 _More About IP Addresses_. An “IP address” is a unique number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you connect to the Internet. It is used to identify your computer’s “location” in cyberspace, so that the information you request can be delivered to you. If you use a dial-up connection or a connection that assigns dynamic IP addresses, your computer will be assigned a new IP address each time you connect to the Internet. If, however, your computer is permanently connected to the Internet using a static IP address, the IP address assigned to your computer will generally be the same each time you use your computer.

IP addresses do not include your name, email address or other information that identifies you personally, but in some cases, they can be used to identify you. For example, if you have registered with this Site, we may link your IP address to account information that identifies you personally. We may also provide your IP address to our third-party service provider who can use it to identify your state and zip code. This gives us valuable demographic information about the individuals who use this Site. Our service providers are bound by contract to use the IP addresses we provide only for this purpose. In addition, if, for example, we suspect fraud or a threat to the security of this Site, we may share our server logs-which contain users’ IP addresses-with the appropriate investigative authorities, who could use that information to trace and identify individuals.

 _Cookies and Similar Technologies_. We use “cookies” and other Web technologies to collect information and support certain features of this Site. For example, we may use these technologies to:

  * collect information about the ways visitors use this Site-which pages they visit, which links they use, and how long they stay on each page;
  * to support the features and functionality of this Site-for example, to save you the trouble of reentering information already in our database or to prompt the settings you established on previous visits; and
  * to personalize your experience when you use this Site.

Generally, the information we collect using these Web technologies does not identify you personally. If, however, you have created a user identity, for example, by registering with this Site, we may link the information we collect using these Web technologies to other information that identifies you personally.

If you do not wish to receive cookies, you may set your browser to reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your computer. You may also delete our cookies as soon as you leave this Site. Although you are not required to accept our cookies when you visit this Site, if you set your browser to reject cookies, you will not be able to use all of the features and functionality of this Site.

## Use of Our Social Networking Tools

If you register as a member of this Site, you will have access to a variety of social networking tools. For example, members of this Site can comment on news stories, create blogs, and submit photographs and videos. As a member of this Site, you can connect with other members through the “Add Me As a Friend” feature. Site members can also send each other both “public” and “private” messages.

Much of the content you submit on or through this Site using our social networking tools is available to the general public. Other social networking tools allow you to restrict the visibility of content you submit to people you have “friended.” However, restricting access in this manner does not guarantee that you will maintain control over personal information you post on or through this Site. It is possible that someone you “friend” will distribute such content to the general public, for example, by posting it on another Web site. Therefore, you should have no expectation of privacy with respect to the content you or others submit on or through this Site using our social networking tools. You should not submit any content you do not wish to make available to the general public, and you must take special care to make sure your submissions comply with our [Terms of Use](https://www.aspentimes.com/terms-of-use/). In particular, your submissions must not violate the privacy or other rights of others.

On certain pages of this Site, we may provide to you a tool to report objectionable content posted by other Site users. If that tool is not available, you can report such content by e-mailing us at [digitalsupport@aspentimes.com](mailto:digitalsupport@aspentimes.com) or by sending a written report to 314 E. Hyman Ave, #101, Aspen, CO 81611. While we do not have any obligation to remove content from this Site merely because of a removal request, we will review all such requests and will remove content that we determine should be removed, in our sole discretion and in accordance with our Terms of Use [insert link] (including this Policy) and applicable law. Please be aware, however, that if the content has already been distributed to other Web sites or published in other media, we will not be able to recapture and delete it. Also, a back-up or residual copy of the content we remove from this Site may remain on back-up servers.

## How We Use Personal Information Collected Through This Site

Generally, we use the personal information we collect through this Site

  * to provide the information, products and services you request;
  * for security, credit or fraud prevention purposes;
  * to provide you with effective customer service;
  * to provide you with a personalized experience when you use our Sites;
  * to contact you with special offers and other information we believe will be of interest to you (in accordance with any privacy preferences you have expressed to us);
  * to contact you with information and notices related to your use of our Sites;
  * to invite you to participate in surveys and provide feedback to us (in accordance with any privacy preferences you have expressed to us);
  * to better understand your needs and interests;
  * to improve the content, functionality and usability of this Site and other sites owned by Swift Communications;
  * to improve our products and services;
  * to improve our marketing and promotional efforts; and
  * for any other purpose identified in an applicable Privacy Notice, click-through agreement or other agreement between you and us.

Please see below for information about the choices you have about the ways we use your personal information.

## How We Use Survey Information

From time to time, we may post a survey on this Site or, if we have your contact information and your consent, we may send you a questionnaire or survey. Your participation in any survey is always voluntary. We compile statistical information from the responses to our surveys. These statistics do not identify you personally. These statistics help us understand the needs and preferences of the groups we serve and improve the content and functionality of this Site. In addition, when we conduct a poll that gauges reader reaction to a particular news event, we may make the results of that poll available on this Site.

## Your Choices

 _In General_. We respect your right to make choices about the ways we collect, use and disclose your personal information. In most cases, we will ask you to indicate your choices at the time we collect your personal information. For example, when you register with this Site, we provide you with an opportunity to “opt out” of receiving certain communications from us. In addition, we will include an “opt out” link in each electronic newsletter or promotional e-mail we send you, so that you can inform us that you do not wish to receive such communications from us in the future.

 _Previously Expressed Preferences_. You may change previously expressed preferences regarding how we use your personal information. If you are a registered member of this Site, you can change certain privacy preferences through your account settings. Otherwise, if at any time you wish to be taken off our mailing lists, please contact us by e-mail at [digitalsupport@aspentimes.com](mailto:digitalsupport@aspentimes.com) or by mail at 314 E. Hyman Ave, #101, Aspen, CO 81611. Please provide your full name, postal address and e-mail address so that we can find you on our mailing lists. Once we have the information we need, we will remove you from our mailing lists as you have requested. Please give us a reasonable amount of time to honor your request.

## How to Access, Update or Correct Your Personal Information

If you are a registered member of this Site, you can access, update or correct your personal information through your account settings. Otherwise, you may need our help. If you wish to access, update or correct your personal information, please contact us by e-mail at [digitalsupport@aspentimes.com](mailto:digitalsupport@aspentimes.com) or by mail at 314 E. Hyman Ave, #101, Aspen, CO 81611. We will respond to you within a reasonable time and, in any case, within the time limits established by applicable law. We may ask you for additional information to verify your identity. In most cases, we will provide access and correct or delete any inaccurate information you discover. In some cases, however, we may limit or deny your request if the law permits or requires us to do so or if we are unable to verify your identify.

## Steps We Take to Safeguard your Personal Information

We maintain reasonable administrative, physical and technological measures to protect the confidentiality and security of personal information you submit on or through this Site. For example, when collecting credit card information for online purchases, we offer secured-service transactions that encrypt your information in transit to thwart others from intercepting or misusing it. Unfortunately, no Web site, server or database is completely secure or “hacker proof.” We therefore cannot guarantee that your personal information will not be disclosed, misused or lost by accident or by the unauthorized acts of others. Further, we cannot control dissemination of personal information you post on or through this Site using our social networking tools, and you should have no expectation of privacy in such information.

## How We Share Your Personal Information With Others

 _Third-Party Vendors_. Swift Communications shares personal information collected through this Site with third-party vendors who act for or on behalf of Swift Communications. For example, we use third-party vendors to design and operate our Web sites, including this Site; to conduct surveys; and to help us with our promotional efforts. These third-party vendors may need information about you to perform their functions. These companies are required by contract to keep your personal information confidential and may use it only to provide services on our behalf.

 _User Generated Content_. As described above, much of the content you submit on or through this Site using our social networking tools is available to the general public. Even if you restrict access to the content you submit, individuals who have access to that content may distribute it to the general public, for example, by posting it to other Web sites. In addition, we may use content you post to public areas of this Site in connection with our news gathering and reporting activities. For example, we may select certain photographs you submit on or through this Site for publication in one of our newspapers. We may or may not use your name in connection with such use, and we may or may not seek your consent before using the content for such purposes. Finally, we may repurpose content you post to public areas of this Site for use in advertising campaigns and other promotions. For all of these reasons, you should have no expectation of privacy with respect to the content you or others submit on or through this Site using our social networking tools.

## AP News Registry

This Web site uses services provided by AP News Registry. AP News Registry collects content usage information and may use cookies in conjunction with this activity.Your continued readership of the Site means you accept the privacy policy of the AP News Registry. Please refer to the AP News Registry privacy policy at <http://www.apnewsregistry.com/privacycenter/servicepolicy.aspx> for further information.

 _Business Transfers_. Your personal information may be transferred to successor organization if, for example, we transfer the ownership or operation of this Site to another organization or if we merge with another organization. If such a transfer occurs, the successor organization’s use of your personal information will still be subject to this Privacy Policy and the privacy preferences you have expressed to us.

 _Compliance With Laws and Protection of Our Rights and the Rights of Others_. We may disclose your personal information when we, in good faith, believe disclosure is appropriate to comply with the law, a court order or a subpoena. We may also disclose your personal information to prevent or investigate a possible crime, such as fraud or identity theft; to protect the security of this Site; to enforce or apply our online [Terms of Use](https://www.aspentimes.com/terms-of-use/) or other agreements; or to protect our own rights or property or the rights, property or safety of our users or others.

 _As Described in a Privacy Notice_. We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as described in any Privacy Notice posted on a page of this Site where you provide that information. By providing your personal information on that page you will be consenting to the disclosure of your personal information as described in that Privacy Notice.

 _As Described in a Click-Through Agreement_. We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as described in any click-through agreement to which you have agreed.

## Children Under the Age of Thirteen

We are proud of this Site and we strive to ensure that it doesn’t offend people of any age. However, this Site is not intended for children or minors under the age of thirteen years without the permission of a parent or guardian. If you believe that a child has submitted personal information on or through this Site without the consent and supervision of a parent or guardian, please contact us by e-mail at [digitalsupport@aspentimes.com](mailto:digitalsupport@aspentimes.com) or by mail at 314 E. Hyman Ave, #101, Aspen, CO 81611 so that we can take appropriate action.

## Advertisements on this Site

Our affiliate advertising companies may utilize “interest-based advertising” that allows them to deliver advertisements to you based on your previous Internet browsing activities, such as visits to an advertiser Web site, and to categorize your browsing activities. To develop interest categories, the companies will recognize the types of Web pages you visit. For example, if you visit a number of sports pages, you may be placed in a “sports enthusiast” interest category and may be presented with advertisements associated with sports in subsequent Internet searches.

Our affiliate advertising companies use cookies and similar Web technologies to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize or optimize advertising content. We do not have access to or control over cookies and other technologies they use. The information practices of these advertisers are outside the scope of this Policy. Please refer to the privacy policies of individual advertisers for additional information.

## Links to Other Sites

This Site may provide links to other Web sites operated by third parties. Because we have no control over third-party Web sites, we are not responsible for the availability of those Web sites and do not endorse and are not responsible or liable for any content, advertising, services, products, or other materials on or available from such Web sites. Swift Communications shall not be responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for any damage or loss caused or alleged to be caused by or in connection with the use of or reliance on any content, advertising, services, products, or other materials on or available from such Web sites. This Policy does not apply to your use of third-party Web sites; your use of such Web sites is subject to the terms and policies of the owner of such Web sites.

## Information for Visitors Accessing Our Sites from Outside the United States

Swift Communications is a U.S. corporation headquartered in the United States. This Site is currently hosted on servers located in the United States, although we reserve the right to relocate this Site to other servers elsewhere in the world. Your personal information may be stored on servers located within the United States or in another country. In addition, we may transfer your personal information to our service providers and others located in the United States or another country for the purposes described in this Policy. Different countries have different privacy laws and requirements, and some provide less legal protection for your personal information than others. Please know, however, that no matter where your personal information is collected, used, transferred or stored, if it was collected through this Policy, it will be protected by the terms of this Policy and any Privacy Notices, or other agreements that apply to you.

BY USING THIS SITE, YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE COLLECTION, USE, AND TRANSFER OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IN OR TO THE UNITED STATES OR TO ANY OTHER COUNTRY IN THE WORLD SUBJECT TO THE TERMS OF THIS POLICY.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us by e-mail at [digitalsupport@aspentimes.com](mailto:digitalsupport@aspentimes.com) or by mail at 314 E. Hyman Ave, #101, Aspen, CO 81611.

fb.us.5092879.01
